Guide to the UE Artifacts Collection, 1970s-1982 UE.17
ULS Archives & Special Collections
UE Artifacts Collection
1970s-1982
ULS Archives & Special Collections
United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America
UE.17
5.34 Linear Feet (6 boxes)
Acquisition Information
T-shirts and hats were donated by Bill Barry in 2002 and 2011. Other portions of the collection were donated by the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This record group contains items produced by the United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, as opposed to the informational or graphic records found in the other record groups of the collection. Included are clothing items produced by the national union and several locals, as well as a bag with the UE logo. Also included is a bust of longtime UE international officer James Matles and embossers with the seals of several locals.
Previous Citation
UE Artifacts Collection, 1970s-1982, UE.17, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Howard Scott Labor Ephemera Collection, 1894-2004, AIS.1999.09, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Electric industry workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Labor unions -- United States; Memorabilia; Labor; United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. Local 107 (Lester, Pa.); United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. Local 128 (Waynesboro, Va.); United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America. Local 141 (Easton, Pa.)
- Bill Barry Artifacts, UE.17.1
  - UE Local 141 Easton, PA, Bill Barry "The Members Run this Union" Jacket (Box 1, Item 1)
  - UE Local 1202 "Unity for Progress" Jacket (Box 1, Item 2)
  - UE Local 277 Baseball Hat (Box 1, Item 3)
  - UE Pen and Pencil Set (Box 1, Item 4)
  - "UE: Organizing the South" Hand Screened T-Shirt, Winston-Salem, NC, 1978 (Box 2, Item 1)
    Scope and Content Notes
    Initially the costs associated with making these first hand-screened shirts were rejected by UE Director of Organization Hugh Harley; however, as the idea and popularity of using locally made shirts like this one grew, the national union realized the potential benefits of their visibility during organizing campaigns.
  - UE Local 128 Waynesboro, VA, Bill Barry Basketball Team T-Shirt, 1978 (Box 2, Item 2)
    In 1978, UE Local 128 started a basketball team as an organizing tactic at Stanley Furniture. This shirt belonged to Bill Barry, an organizer who served as their coach for one season.
  - UE Local 141 Easton, PA, Bill Barry "The Members Run this Union" T-Shirt, 1982 (Box 2, Item 3)
    This T-shirt was worn during an organizing campaign at Cooper Industries, Penn Pump in Easton, Pennsylvania.
  - UE Local 107 Lester, PA, T-Shirt, 1982 (Box 2, Item 4)
  - "Argo Workers Need a Contract" UE T-Shirt with Mickey Mouse, Berwick, PA, 1982 (Box 2, Item 5)
    This T-shirt was worn during an extended campaign for the first contract for workers at Argo, Inc. in Berwick, Pennsylvania.
  - "Hey Ronnie, Protect Social Security" UE T-Shirt with Mickey Mouse, 1981 (Box 2, Item 6)
    Organizer Bill Barry screen printed shirts like this one for UE locals in northeastern Pennsylvania for Solidarity Day. This particular shirt came from Local 170 in Mountaintop, Pennsylvania.
  - "Vote Yes! UE" T-Shirt by Ron Carver, New Bedford, MA, 1981 (Box 2, Item 7)
  - "The Silver Bullet Saloon" T-Shirt, Nescopeck, PA (Box 2, Item 8)
    This T-shirt is from a bar opened by Ralph DeFabo, an officer of UE Local 175 at Argo, Inc., after the shop closed.
- UE National Office Artifacts, UE.17.2
  - UE Local 284 Seal Embosser (Box 3)
  - UE Local 237 Seal Embosser (Box 4)
  - UE Local 1002 Seal Embosser (Box 5)
  - Bust of James Matles by R. Ekins, 1975 (Box 6)
    This bust was used to cast a metal plaque memorializing Matles' contributions to the UE and the labor movement.